Alpesh Gevariya

https://www.designwithalpesh.com

alpesh.gevariya.15@gmail.com



ABOUT ME

A designer, with 8+ years of professional experience in UX/UI design, worked in a wide range of environments from start-ups and IT consultancies. I am passionate about bringing inclusivity into design solutions by bridging physical and digital worlds to help businesses to identify the changing needs of users.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER UX/UI, ESCALE SOLUTIONS

India (Jan 2021 - Present)

- Synced with product owner to identify user profiles, conducted user research and set-up ideation workshops with design team and implemented **5+ product features**.
- Contributed to the **Design System**, designed components for consistency throughout product.
- Designed user interfaces and experiences for a wide range of clients across industries, including healthcare, e-commerce, and education.
- Conducted user research with over 100 participants and designed a new website, resulting in a 16% increase in revenue.

HEAD OF UX/UI DESIGN DEPARTMENT, CORUSCATE SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD. India (Jul 2019 - Apr 2021)

- Led a team of **8+ creative people** for **4 years** and was responsible for task management, regular meetings, task allocation, interviews, appraisals, managing deliverables, and decision making.
- Collaborated with the product development team to design and implement highly interactive, dataintensive web applications and created 250+ mobile app UI designs.
- Illustrated design ideas using sitemaps, storyboards, and process flows.
- Conducted interviews with 100+ end users and designed a new website and its revenue growth by 16%.
- Received 95% positive feedback on 17 completed projects.

UX/UI DESIGNER, CORUSCATE SOLUTIONS PVT. LTD.

India (May 2013 - Apr 2016)

- Responsible for 1.2 million+ monthly visitors to give the best user experience with my expertise.
- Invented 50+ marketing collateral and improved engagement ratio by 20%.
- Worked with developers and product managers to develop 9+ new products that brought in a 137%.
- Conducted user research with over 100 participants and designed a new website, resulting in a 16% increase in revenue.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Applications (B.C.A.)

(2016 - 2019)

Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan University, India

UX/UI CERTIFICATION - 9 months

(2012-2013)

Red & White Multimedia Education, India

CERTIFICATION

Figma (2023)

WeLoveNoCode

AdobeXD (2023)

Uxcel

UX/UI Design (2023)

WeLoveNoCode

UX concepts validation (2023)

intouxdesign

SKILLS

Design Thinking Tools, Quantitative and Qualitative Research, Problem Definition and Hypothesis Creation, Personas, Stakeholder Mapping, Information Architecture, Wire-framing, Prototyping and Usability Testing Methods, Heuristic Analysis, UX Writing, Storytelling and Power Point Presentations, Service Design Blueprint, Business Model Canvas, UI Design, Visual Design and Facilitating and designing Workshops.

TOOLS

Figma, AdobeXD, Sketch, Zeplin, Jira, Confluence, Notion, Miro, Mural, Webflow, Wix, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, MS Office, Google Suite, Power Point, Key Note, Shopify

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

English: Advanced

German: Elementary A1, (learning A2)

Hindi: Native